Elliott Lockwood

(713) 562 - 6480 | lockwood721@gmail.com | Austin, TX - 78704

GitHub: www.github.com/elock721 | Heroku: elliottjlockwood@herokuapp.com

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/elliottjlockwood

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with a 4-year bachelor's degree and a background in oil and gas. Always referred to by coworkers as a hardworking, adaptable, exceptional team player. Effective at approaching every job task or challenge with a combination of creativity and my passion for problem solving.

Technical Skills

Front End: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, React JS, Responsive Design, Local Storage **Back End:** MySQL, MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js), User Authentication

Deployment: Heroku, Github

Web Development Projects

ViVi Virtual Waiting Room August 2020

GitHub Repo: https://github.com/Diemrosely/project3
Deployed App: https://viviproject3.herokuapp.com/

A virtual waiting roommate built with React JS to help doctors and patients minimize unnecessary contact

• Frontend Engineer & Github/Heroku Deployment lead

• React JS, React Bootstrap, MySQL, Express, Node JS, CSS, Github, Heroku

Find My Fare July 2020

GitHub Repo: https://github.com/elock721/Project-2-Idea
Deployed App: https://find-my-fare.herokuapp.com/

This application helps users in the Austin area to find their favorite food trucks

- Backend engineer & Github/Heroku Deployment lead
- Javascript, SQL/MySQL Workbench, CSS Grid, Google Maps API, Node JS, Heroku, Github

Fish Guide Friend June 2020

GitHub Repo: https://github.com/elock721/Fish-Guide-Friend/ **Deployed App:** https://mcui1997.github.io/Fish-Guide-Friend/

- An application helping users find the highest rated fishing guides in a specific area
- UI Engineer responsible for creating user friendly interface
- HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, JSON, AJAX, APIs, Github

Experience

Floor Hand: Spencer Ogden

01/2019 - 04/2020

- Headed comprehensive pre job safety meetings to delegate tasks to appropriate parties and mitigate all job risks
- Coordinated with the drilling fluid's engineer to maintain the integrity of the drilling fluid weight & viscosity at all times
- Effectively operated various types of drilling equipment to maximize drilling efficiency for every client

Bar Staff: Houston Hospitality

11/2016 - 12/2018

- Taught new hires all necessary roles & responsibilities for maintaining restaurant's maximum operational efficiency
- Constantly assessed liquor supply of bar to ensure restaurant never lost an opportunity to profit

Floor Hand: Ensco Offshore

10/2013 - 06/2016

- Headed comprehensive pre job safety meetings to delegate tasks to appropriate parties and mitigate all job risks
- Coordinated with the drilling fluid's engineer to maintain the integrity of the drilling fluid weight & viscosity at all times
- Effectively operated various types of drilling equipment to maximize drilling efficiency for every client

Education

Full Stack Web Development Certificate: University of Texas - Austin, TX 2020

Bachelor of General Studies in History: University of Kansas - Lawrence, KS

Volunteer Experience

Sorting Volunteer: Central Texas Food Bank

04/2020 - Present

• I sort through donated foods and goods to create packages for those that are experiencing food insecurity in Central Texas.

Mentor Volunteer: Engage the Vision

03/2018 - 05/2019

• I volunteered on available Friday afternoons during the school year at Martin Luther King Elementary in Los Angeles, California to act as a positive male role model and mentor for at-risk, underprivileged children.

Conservation Volunteer: African Impact

04/2016

• I spent 3 weeks volunteering on a wildlife conservation project in Victoria Falls, Zimbabwe focused on big cats. I also spent time at the local orphanage providing any and all possible support to the severely impoverished orphans.

Eagle Scout: Troop 125 - Houston, Texas